A modest gift
Скромный дар
Just a token of sincerity
просто знак уважения
The Wutu people spend their whole lives
Уну всю жизнь
Living on horseback
живут в седле
We Xuan people are different
а мы люди Сюань другие
So I made improvements
Я по нашим обычаям
According to Xuan people's habits
коечто доработал
Specially sought skilled craftsmen
специально поручил мастеру
To forge a pair
изготовить
Eagerly brought them
спешил принести
For the general to try
чтобы генерал попробовал
I heard these past two days
Слышал в последние дни
Your Highness
Ваше Высочество
Has been busy writing inscriptions for people
был занят надписями
It really
должно быть
Must be tiring
это требует немалых усилий
Hobby
Хобби
Just a hobby
всего лишь увлечение
I remember
Помню
Last year the court discussed going north
в прошлом году обсуждали поход на север
But because the treasury was empty
но изза пустой казны
No money, no grain
без денег и провианта
It came to nothing in the end
всё сошло на нет
Looking at it this way
Глядя на происходящее
From last year to this year
от прошлого года до нынешнего
Elder brother has
старший брат
Been managing the household well
умеет вести дела
General
Генерал
Rarely returns to the capital
так редко бывает в столице
Even if I treat myself poorly
Даже если придётся ущемить себя
I cannot treat poorly
не могу обделить
The pillars of the state
опору государства
Your Highness overpraises
Ваше Высочество преувеличиваете
You humble your subject too much
Я недостоин таких похвал
I also ask
Также прошу
Prince of Jin to be cautious with words
принца Цзиня быть сдержаннее в словах
The inner hall is about to begin the banquet
Внутри уже начинается пир
Prince of Jin
Принц Цзинь
Prince of Ning
Принц Нин
Please
Прошу
Please, please
Прошу прошу